Mikhail Rusakovich

Highly motivated person with 3 years experience in software development with broad experience in working with Java-based tools and frameworks on different platforms. Mostly experienced in developing of full stack enterprise- and web- applications. Also I always have a great passion for learning new technologies, algorithms and really enjoy all kinds of open-source stuff.

Contacts:

• Tel: +375 29 1798417

• Email: mikhail.complete@gmail.com

• Skype: mikhail.complete

• My legal name: Mikhail Rusakovich

Skills

- Java, Groovy, C, PL/SQL, JavaEE (JSF, EJB, JPA, Servlets, JSP, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, JNDI, JMS, CDI), JAXB, JCE, Spring, GWT, Hibernate, ActiveMQ, Apache CXF, JUnit, Mockito, Arquillian, Maven, Ant
- Basic HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery
- Weblogic, JBoss (WildFly), Tomcat, Glassfish
- SVN, Git
- Jenkins CI, Sonatype Nexus

Work experience

• Java Developer, Sep 2012–Jul 2013, Dec 2014 - present

Developing and support TOPBY.by B2B EDI message provider which includes numerous conversion and connecting modules between customers located throughout the country.

Also taking part in architecture development.

- Company: SoftClub, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Developing, testing, external system researching, reporting, integration with external systems
- Tools & technologies used: Java, C, JavaScript, JNI, Weblogic, Tomcat, Arquillian, ActiveMQ, Apache CXF, Spring, Groovy, JPA, JDBC, JAXB, XML, XSD, XSLT, Maven, SVN, Jira, NSIS Scriptable Install System

• Java Developer, Jan 2014–Dec 2014

Homecredit Bank Belarus ibank retail. Internet banking for individuals.

- Company: SoftClub, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Frontend and backend developing, testing, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Java, JSF (ICEfaces), JSP, EJB, Hibernate, JBoss, Dozer, Ant, jQuery, prototype.js, SVN, Jira
- Java Developer, Jul 2013–Jan 2014

BUTB.by Belarusian Universal Commodity Exchange. Exchange trading system.

- Company: SoftClub, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Backend and service developing, testing, reporting, integration with external systems
- Tools & technologies used: Java, EJB, JPA, Servlets, Glassfish, Oracle PL/SQL, SOAP, Velocity, XDocReport, Ant, SVN, Jira

Open source

• https://bitbucket.org/mikhail_complete/smarthome

SmartHouse project is an attempt to create a universal platform for the management of home devices using popular interface interaction. At the moment, you can work with devices on the serial, USB and 1-wire protocols, and survey your real estate using a large number of supported cameras. To add support for the device is quite easy - you just need to add it in one of the configuration files. Also, some kinds of mock-devices are available for development stage.

From ideas development to realization.

- Tools & technologies used: Java, C, GWT, Jetty, Spring, RMI, JNI, Bootstrap, JQuery,
 WebSocket, Maven, JUnit, Mockito, Cucumber, Selenium WebDriver, Git
- https://github.com/creepid/DocsReporter

Documents reporting system in docx, odt, pdf, xhtml and pptx formats extending XDocReport project and using Spring Framework. Supported template formats: .docx, .odt and .pptx

- $Tools\ \mathcal E$ $technologies\ used:$ Java, Spring, Velocity, Freemarker, JUnit, Mockito, Maven, Git

Education

• Belarusian State University, 2008–2013 Diploma in Researching Physics.

Appendix

- https://github.com/creepid
- https://bitbucket.org/mikhail_complete